Women's Action Alliance Records, 1970-1996
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Events
    - Theater benefits (includes Lily Tomlin, Wendy Wasserstein, Gloria Steinem) (Box 296, Folder 10)
    - Women's Roasts
      - Geraldine Ferraro, 1985 (includes Gloria Steinem and Sandra Bernhardt) (Box 296, Folder 11)
      - Liz Smith, 1986 (includes Kay Ballard, Helen Gurley Brown, Marvin Hamlisch, Diane Sawyer, Beverly Sills, Holland Taylor, Kathleen Turner and Ruth Westheimer) (Box 297, Folder 1)
      - Donna Shalala, 1987 (includes Bella Abzug, Geraldine Ferraro, Marvin Hamlisch, Gloria Steinem) (Box 297, Folder 2)
      - Pat Schroeder, 1988 (includes Gloria Steinem, Loretta Swit, Ruth Westheimer, and Julia Sweeney) (Box 297, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified events (includes Gloria Steinem, Jane Williamson, Wanda Wooten) (Box 297, Folder 4)
  - Portraits associated with unidentified projects (includes Gloria Steinem, Selena, Brenda Feigen Fasteau) (Box 297, Folder 5)
  - Projects
    - Economics: Women and Work Exposition (includes prints, contact sheets, and slides) 1978-79 (Box 297-298)
    - Education
      - Non-Sexist Childhood Development
        - General
          - Equal Play artwork (Box 298, Folder 9)
          - Non-Sexist Education for Young Children artwork (Box 298, Folder 10)
          - Play people (Box 298, Folder 11)
          - Miscellany (Box 298, Folder 12)
        - Conferences
          - Conference on Non-Sexist Early Education, 1976 (Box 299, Folder 1)
          - Institute for Equal Early Education (Box 299, Folder 2)
        - Beginning Equal (Box 299, Folder 3)
        - Project REED
          - "Access to Equality" conference (Box 299, Folder 4)
          - Educational Alliance Child Care Center (Box 299, Folder 5)
          - NAB meeting (Box 299, Folder 6)
        - Resource photos
          - General (Box 299, Folder 7)
          - Children, at play, at work, and Native American (Box 299, Folder 8-10)
          - Feminist Resources for Equal Education (Box 300, Folder 1)
          - Mainstreaming adults and children (Box 300, Folder 2-3)
          - Men in the Nurturing Role (Box 300, Folder 4-5)
          - People at Work (Box 300, Folder 6-7)
          - Women and sports (Box 300, Folder 8)
    - Health
      - "The Body Alliance: A Wellness Day for Women" (Box 300, Folder 9)
      - "Listen to Us: Multicultural Prenatal Drug & Alcohol Prevention Program" (Box 300, Folder 10)
      - "Making the Connection: Preventing Alcohol, Tobacco, and Other Drug Problems in the Context of Women's Lives," 1993 (Box 300, Folder 11)
      - Project Awareness: Bosom Buddies (Box 300, Folder 12)
      - Project TELL: Domestic Violence Awareness, 1994 (Box 300, Folder 13)
      - Resource Mothers, 1994-95 (Box 301, Folder 1-2)
      - Women's Alcohol & Drug Project oatmeal facials, 1995 (Box 301, Folder 3)
    - Women's Centers Project
      - Workshops: Everywoman's Center (Amherst, MA) and New Haven Women's Liberation Center technical assistance workshops, 1980 (Box 301, Folder 4-5)
      - Coalition for the Conference on Women's Centers, 1982 (Box 301, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 301, Folder 7)
- SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL
  - Audiotapes, [ORIGINALS RESTRICTED - Copies must be made for research use]
    - General
      - Corporate presentation telephone tape, 31 January 1977 (Box 301, Folder 1)
      - Executive Director Ruth Abram, National Council on Philanthropy (Box 301, Folder 2)
      - PNCIT[?] Meeting, 18 March 1982 (Box 301, Folder 3-6)
      - PAWS[?]/WAA Meeting, 4 January 1982 (Box 301, Folder 7-8)
      - WAA Board Meeting, 4 March 1983 (Box 301, Folder 9-10)
      - "Workshop Planning and Organizational Strategy" (2 tapes), undated (Box 301, Folder 11-12)
      - Unidentified conference session, "Personal Solutions and Alternatives," (includes Marianne "Jolly" Robinson's autobiographical reflections), undated (Box 301, Folder 13)
    - Projects
      - Women at Work Exposition, 1979 (25 tapes of sessions) (Box 302-304)
      - Non-Sexist Child Development
        - General (12 tapes, including 10 instructional units on sex-role stereotyping for teachers and teacher educators and a telephone interview with Liz Demarest), undated (Box 304, Folder 39-50)
        - Conferences (7 tapes), 1973-81, undated (Box 304-305)
        - Dialogue re: sex roles in child rearing, 1973 (Box 305, Folder 58)
        - Interactions with children re: careers, undated (Box 305, Folder 59)
        - Parent meeting, Lincoln Square, undated (Box 305, Folder 60)
        - Recollections of parent meeting of Amalgamated Nursery School parents, 1973 (Box 305, Folder 61)
        - Teacher's Center meeting, Chicago, undated (Box 305, Folder 62)
        - "Beginning Equal," 1982-83
          - General (35 tapes) 1982-83 (Box 305-307)
          - BJ's Kids (Box 307, Folder 98-105)
          - Bronx Teen Group Interview, 5 Oct 1982 (Box 308, Folder 106)
        - East Harlem Caregivers, 1983 (Box 308, Folder 107-110)
        - Hunt's Point, 1982 (Box 308, Folder 111-116)
        - Other
          - "Boy Meets Girl" (Free to Be, with Marlo Thomas) (Box 308, Folder 117)
          - Research report: Images of Males and Females in Elementary School Textbooks, 1976, by Lenore Weitzman and Diane Rizzo (Box 308, Folder 118)
          - "Sisterhood of Single Black Mothers," interview, 6 Oct 1982 (Box 308, Folder 119)
        - Project R.E.E.D.
          - General, 1981-82 (Box 120-121)
          - Materials Workshops
            - New York University, 23 Oct, undated (Box 308-309)
            - Yaguina View elementary school, 1981 (Box 309, Folder 125)
            - Location unknown, 12 Nov 1981 (Box 309, Folder 126)
            - Unidentified teacher meeting/interview, undated (Box 309, Folder 127)
          - Pilot Testing
            - General
              - King Children's Center, Berkeley, CA, 11 Nov 1981 (Box 309, Folder 128)
              - Garden City, NJ, May 1981 (Box 309, Folder 129)
              - Passaic, NJ, Head Start, Jun 1981 (Box 309, Folder 130-131)
              - Educational Alliance, 1981 (Box 309, Folder 132)
              - Little Red Schoolhouse, New York City, Jul 1981 (Box 309, Folder 133-134)
            - Curriculum Workshops: Glen Falls, NY, and Freehold, NJ (Box 309, Folder 135-138)
            - Parents Workshop
              - Jersey City, NJ, 1980 or 1981 (Box 309, Folder 139)
              - Vignettes for parents workshop, 1 Jun 1981 (Box 310, Folder 140)
            - Field testing
              - Dade County, FL Head Start, 13 Jan 1982 (Box 310, Folder 141-142)
              - Ft. Lauderdale, FL, Jan-Mar 1982 (Box 310, Folder 143-145)
              - Miami, FL Head Start post- test meeting, 11 Mar 1982 (Box 310, Folder 146)
              - Newport, OR, 10 Nov 1981 and 7 Jan 1982 (Box 310, Folder 147-150)
              - Portland, OR Head Start, 9 Nov 1981 and 6 Jan 1982 (Box 310, Folder 151-152)
              - Quincy, MA 1982 (Box 310-311)
              - Reidsville, NC, Apr and May 1982 (Box 311, Folder 158-159)
            - Manual: Ellen Rubin's article for "Creating a New Mainstream, undated (Box 311, Folder 160)
          - "Access to Equality" conference, June 1982 (Box 311, Folder 161-172)
        - Project T.R.E.E
          - Film workshops, 1978, undated (Box 311, Folder 311-312)
          - Language workshops, Oct 1978 (Box 312, Folder 175-177)
          - Literature workshops, undated (Box 312, Folder 178-180)
        - Filmstrip: "A Nonsexist Curriculum in Early Childhood," includes audiotapes and filmstrip (Box 312, Folder 181-183)
        - Equal Play interviews with Karen Welch, Karen Hewett[?], and Victor Dye, 1981 (Box 312, Folder 184-185)
        - NSCD unidentified (Box 312, Folder 186-189)
      - Children of Single Parents in the Schools, 1988
        - Divorced/Widowed Mom's Group (Box 312, Folder 190-191)
        - Divorced/Separated/Never-Married Women (Box 313, Folder 192-193)
        - Divorced/Separated/Never-Married Women (Brooklyn YWCA) (Box 313, Folder 194-196)
        - McBurney interview (Box 313, Folder 197)
        - Teachers group. 8 August 1988 (Box 313, Folder 198-199)
        - Kids #3, Flatbush YMCA (Box 313, Folder 200)
      - National Women's Agenda Project
        - Press conferences, 19 June, 25 July 1975; 2 December 1975 (Box 313, Folder 201-202)
        - Los Estereotipos (Stereotyping of women on television), undated (Box 313, Folder 203)
        - Radio programs, 1976 (Box 313, Folder 204-206)
        - [Task forces?], "Econ Power/Criminal Justice/Childcare/Media/Politics," undated (Box 313, Folder 207)
      - Women's Centers Projects technical assistance workshops
        - Everywoman's Center, Amherst, MA, undated (Box 313-314)
        - New Haven Women's Liberation Center, undated (Box 314, Folder 212-217)
  - Unidentifed (Box 314, Folder 218-219)
  - Reel-to-reel audiotapes, [Originals restricted - please use tapes labeled "Research Copies"]
    - Copy of audio cassette tape #118 (Box 315, Folder 1)
    - Copy of audio cassette tapes #204-206 (Box 315, Folder 2-4)
  - Computer disks
    - 20 7.5"x3.25" disks (unknown format), administration and miscellany (Box 315)
    - 17 3.5" disks, administration and Women's Alcohol and Drug Education Project (Box 315)
    - 34 5.25" disks, Children of Single Parents in the Schools (Box 315)
  - Microfiche of Beginning Equal (Box 315)
  - Videotapes, [Originals restricted - use Research copies in box 316a][see also audiotapes #181-183 for Non-Sexist Child Devment filmstrip]
    - Profile of Women's Action Alliance, March 1976 (2 copies, Beta and VHS) (Box 316, Folder 1)
    - Women at Work Exposition, 1978 (2 copies, Beta and VHS) (Box 316, Folder 2)
    - Children of Single Parents in the Schools (2 tapes: one a promotional video from Deerfield Video Productions, and the other, "Coke Is Not It!," an anti-drug-abuse video) (Box 316, Folder 3-4)
    - Computer Equity Expert project (3 tapes, 1 Beta, 2 VHS) (Box 316, Folder 5)
    - Women's Alcohol and Drug Education Project's program Listen to Us/Eschuchemos, 1994 (VHS tape and 2 duplicates) (Box 316, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous: Rosie Radiator, profile of woman tap dancer, undated (Box 316, Folder 7)
    - Research copies for all of tapes in 316 (VHS and DVD) (Box 316a)
- OVERSIZE, .75 linear ft.
  Oversize material contains resource photographs from the Non-Sexist Child Development Project [See SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS], promotional posters, organizational flow charts, office floor plans, and memorabilia, including buttons, erasers, and tote bags.
  - Women's Agenda galleys; photographs; calendars; posters; floor plans; flow charts (Box 317)
  - Framed certificate and memorabilia, including tote bags, erasers, and buttons (Box 318)